[
{"test": "sentence", "question": "The bus \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. late.", "option": ["arrives", "arriving", "arrive"], "answer": "arrived"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Cloe \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. for her turn.", "option": ["waiting", "waits", "wait"], "answer": "waited"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "He loves \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.soccer", "option": ["plays", "play", "played"], "answer": "playing"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Rahul \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.ramen", "option": ["love", "loved", "loving"], "answer": "loves"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "-\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. your work", "option": ["Did", "Doing", "Does"], "answer": "Do"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "When I \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. up, the sun was yet to \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. the sky.", "option": ["Wake-lighting", "woke-lights", "waking-lighted"], "answer": "woke-light"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "The police.............. after the crime \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.place", "option": ["arrived- has taken", "arrived- had taken", "arrive- has taken"], "answer": "arrive- had taken"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "If you\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.the cake, we can \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. an extra piece for later", "option": ["liked-packing", "pack-liked", "liked-pack"], "answer": "like-pack"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Before you\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.to bed, finish \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. the dishes", "option": ["goes-do", "go-do", "gone-done"], "answer": "go-doing"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Even though it was \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026., they \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. their trip", "option": ["rains-starts", "raining-starting", "rained-starting"], "answer": "raining-started"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "We would \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.to visit your family home, provided there is no heavy traffic.", "option": ["liked", "loved", "loving"], "answer": "love"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "They did not \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.until the rain had \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["moved-stop", "moves-stops", "moving-stopped"], "answer": "move-stopped"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "My friend left the country because she \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. a fresh start.", "option": ["needing", "needs", "need"], "answer": "needed"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. hay while the sun \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["make-shining", "maked-shines", "making-shine"], "answer": "make-shines"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "What is imperative sentence?", "option": ["Sentence that commands", "Sentence that forbids", "Sentence that makes request"], "answer": "all of above."},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Give me a pencil.", "option": ["interrogative sentence", "simple sentence", "none of the above"], "answer": "imperative sentence"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "You were meant to be back \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["yesterday.", "yesterday?", "yesterday,"], "answer": "yesterday!"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Jeepers! You scared the life out of me!", "option": ["simple sentence", "imperative sentence", "none of the above"], "answer": "Exclamatory sentence"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "We \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["wins!", "winning!", "win!"], "answer": "won!"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Do you want to go there?", "option": ["exclamatory sentence", "Simple sentence", "Imperative sentence"], "answer": "Interrogative sentence"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Did you see her\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["Did you see her,", "Did you see her!", "Did you see her."], "answer": "Did you see see her?"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "What is interrogative sentence?", "option": ["Sentence that represents feeling", "Sentence that makes request,", "All of above"], "answer": "Sentence that asks question"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Alex is a good baseball player.", "option": ["All of above except none", "Interrogative sentence", "None"], "answer": "Declarative sentence"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "He \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.the Rockers club.", "option": ["played for", "plays or", "plays in"], "answer": "plays on"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "He always gives his best effort in the team.", "option": ["Exclamatory sentence,", "Simple sentence,", "Interrogative sentence"], "answer": "Declarative sentence"},
{"test": "sentence", "question": "Declarative sentence is defined as", "option": ["declares action", "assertive sentence", "declares statement"], "answer": "all of the above"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "What is part of speech?", "option": ["Classification by role", "Classification by function", "None"], "answer": "All except none"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "Which one is part of speech?", "option": ["Conditionals", "Numbers", "Tense"], "answer": "Noun"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "\u201cTO\u201d is sub division of \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. Speech.", "option": ["conjunction", "verb", "adverb"], "answer": "Preposition"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "Speech is further divided into \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["10 types", "9 types", "7 types"], "answer": "8 types"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "Beautiful is \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["Pronoun", "Noun", "Adverb"], "answer": "Adjective"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "'Suman' is brilliant student.", "option": ["conjunction", "adjective", "adverb"], "answer": "Noun"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "I love both burger 'and' pizza.", "option": ["Adverb", "Verb", "Preposition"], "answer": "Conjunction"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "Oh! that looks painful.", "option": ["Preposition", "Adjective", "Verb"], "answer": "Interjection"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "'They' are helpful.", "option": ["Verb", "Adverb", "Noun"], "answer": "Pronoun"},
{"test": "speech", "question": "France is 'in' Europe.", "option": ["Conjunction", "Verb", "Tense"], "answer": "Preposition"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Noun are divided into \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 types.", "option": ["6 types.", "9 types", "7 types"], "answer": "8 types"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "\u201cBoth of us live in thali.\u201d The sentence has", "option": ["Countable noun", "Common noun,", "Construct noun"], "answer": "Proper noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Proper noun begins with \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026", "option": ["none of above.", "Small letters", "Comma letter"], "answer": "Capital letter"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "My name is 'Suman'.", "option": ["Common noun,", "None of above.", "Countable noun"], "answer": "Proper noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Choose the proper noun from the given sentence \u201cRakesh is watching a movie in his device.\u201d", "option": ["His", "Device", "Movie"], "answer": "Rakesh"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "'Titanic' is great movie.", "option": ["Common noun,", "Collective noun", "Abstract noun"], "answer": "Proper noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 is an engineer.", "option": ["He", "She", "Ram"], "answer": "All of the above."},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "They are happy.", "option": ["Concrete noun", "Collective noun", "Proper noun"], "answer": "Common noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Choose common noun.", "option": ["Kathmandu", "They", "None"], "answer": "All except none"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Choose common noun \u201c I live in Pokhara.\u201d", "option": ["I", "Live", "None"], "answer": "Pokhara"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "He lives in Sydney.", "option": ["Proper noun", "Concrete noun", "Collective noun"], "answer": "Common noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "He plays for Kolkata in IPL.", "option": ["Proper noun", "Concrete noun", "Collective noun"], "answer": "Common noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "He plays for Dhaka in BPL.", "option": ["Concrete noun", "Collective noun", "Proper noun"], "answer": "Common noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Michael Clarke is his 'mentor'.", "option": ["Concrete noun", "Collective noun", "Proper noun"], "answer": "Common noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Material noun is defined as", "option": ["Intangible noun", "Countable noun", "Uncountable noun"], "answer": "Tangible noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "I broke by cricket bat.", "option": ["Abstract noun", "Proper noun", "Common noun"], "answer": "Material noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "The pen is out of ink.", "option": ["Proper noun", "Common noun", "Uncountable noun"], "answer": "Material noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Your shirt has a 'button' short.", "option": ["Countable noun", "Collective noun", "Uncountable noun"], "answer": "Material noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "This ring is made of gold and diamond.", "option": ["Countable noun", "Uncountable noun", "Collective noun"], "answer": "Material noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Hatred is \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["Concrete noun", "Common noun", "Collective noun"], "answer": "Abstract noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Chair\u2019 is \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026", "option": ["Countable noun", "Concrete noun", "Proper noun"], "answer": "All of the above"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 is Compound noun.", "option": ["Mother", "Father", "Sister"], "answer": "Brother-in-law"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Compound noun is defined as\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["Word with single noun", "Sentence with double noun", "None"], "answer": "Word with more than one noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Abstract nouns refers \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["Ideas", "Conditions", "Qualities"], "answer": "All of above"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Which of the following are countable noun.", "option": ["None", "Truth", "Star"], "answer": "Pen"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. is Non-countable noun.", "option": ["None", "Concrete noun", "Common noun"], "answer": "Abstract noun"},
{"test": "Noun", "question": "Singular noun represents\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["Women", "Children\u2019s", "Men"], "answer": "Duck"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "Pronoun are used as .............................", "option": ["Replacement for adverb", "Replacement for preposition", "Replacement for verb"], "answer": "Replacement for noun"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. is helpful.", "option": ["Them", "We", "They"], "answer": "He"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "He also loved \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 and cared about them.", "option": ["This", "Their", "They"], "answer": "Them"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "It made \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. very popular.", "option": ["His", "They", "Their"], "answer": "Him"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "The queen could not stand \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["Them", "Guard.", "Ram"], "answer": "It"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "She began to despise \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["We", "I", "His"], "answer": "Him"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "She was jealous of \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["Their", "They", "We"], "answer": "Her"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "But\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. always respected\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..and treated her with honor.", "option": ["Him-him", "They-him", "Him-they,"], "answer": "He-her,"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "The king and Ned could not understand\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["He", "We", "Their"], "answer": "Me"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. started plotting against \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["it-them", "they-this", "he-their"], "answer": "She-them"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "The orange balls are\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["her", "him", "they"], "answer": "hers"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "The while balls are \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026...", "option": ["They", "It", "We"], "answer": "His"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "The red bat is \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026...", "option": ["that", "they", "them"], "answer": "theirs"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "The blue bat is ..........................", "option": ["them", "it", "him"], "answer": "ours"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "Is this your book? That one is \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026...", "option": ["I", "my", "me"], "answer": "mine"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "Here is my book. Where\u2019s \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..?", "option": ["none of above", "you", "your"], "answer": "yours"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "I don\u2019t need your help while I can do It \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026....", "option": ["Itself", "Themselves", "Ourselves"], "answer": "Myself"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "I cut \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026... when I was shaving.", "option": ["Itself", "Ourselves", "Themselves"], "answer": "Myself"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "She blames\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. for that incident.", "option": ["myself", "themselves", "ourselves"], "answer": "herself"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "Don\u2019t hurt\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 by playing carelessly.", "option": ["myself", "herself", "themselves"], "answer": "yourself"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "We have enjoyed \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026...", "option": ["myself", "themselves", "himself"], "answer": "ourselves"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "You boys should make it \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..", "option": ["myself", "themselves", "himself"], "answer": "yourselves"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "Don\u2019t blame \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. for this.", "option": ["myself", "themselves", "himself"], "answer": "yourself"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "I heard stories \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026were not good at all.", "option": ["that", "whom", "it"], "answer": "this"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "Give me the book\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 is on the table.", "option": ["whose", "where", "when"], "answer": "which"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "The person \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. you met yesterday is a doctor.", "option": ["whose", "where", "when"], "answer": "whom"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "I bought a cricket bat\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. belonged to Rajesh Hamal.", "option": ["when", "where", "whose"], "answer": "which"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "The questions \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. have been asked cannot be answered.", "option": ["None", "it", "this"], "answer": "that"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "I don\u2019t know\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. bat it was.", "option": ["whom", "when", "where"], "answer": "whose"},
{"test": "Pronoun", "question": "We made a deal\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..is satisfactory.", "option": ["whose", "where", "when"], "answer": "which"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "Adjective describes\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["Noun", "Pronoun", "None"], "answer": "All except none"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "I have \u201820\u2019 bucks in my wallet.", "option": ["Interrogative adjective", "Demonstrative adjective", "Proper adjective"], "answer": "Quantitative adjective"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "They have \u2018three\u2019 children.", "option": ["Proper adjective", "Interrogative adjective", "Demonstrative adjective"], "answer": "Quantitative adjective"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "You should have completed the \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 task.", "option": ["this", "that", "three"], "answer": "whole"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "Demonstrative adjective directly refers to\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.", "option": ["That", "These", "Those"], "answer": "All of above"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "Give me \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 blue water bottle", "option": ["their", "them", "this"], "answer": "that"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 time I won\u2019t fail you.", "option": ["that", "their", "them"], "answer": "this"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "I want \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 gorgeous marbles.", "option": ["that", "their", "these"], "answer": "those"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "I wanted to propose you\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.day.", "option": ["those", "these", "their"], "answer": "that"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 mangoes are rotting.", "option": ["Those", "that", "their"], "answer": "these"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "I can\u2019t forget \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.. incident.", "option": ["those", "these", "their"], "answer": "that"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "The students of class seven submitted ............................ assignment.", "option": ["there", "them", "this"], "answer": "their"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "I could not understand \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026intentions.", "option": ["hers", "him", "he"], "answer": "her"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026thoughts are too complex.", "option": ["hers", "he", "him"], "answer": "her"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "They are proud to be Indian", "option": ["Proud", "Be", "They"], "answer": "Indian"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "These are Indian toys.", "option": ["These", "Are", "Toys"], "answer": "Indian"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "Japanese cars are best.", "option": ["best", "are", "cars"], "answer": "japanese"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "Korean drama are have long episode.", "option": ["episode", "long", "drama"], "answer": "korean"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "American helicopters are awesome in design.", "option": ["Helicopters", "Are", "None of these"], "answer": "American"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "The adjective is ____.", "option": ["Don\u2019t", "Jump", "From"], "answer": "Running"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "The adjective is ____.", "option": ["Chocolate", "Baby", "Give"], "answer": "Crying"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "The flying airplanes look very beautiful from our roof. The adjective is ____.", "option": ["Airplanes", "Roof", "Look"], "answer": "Flying"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "He is an experienced painter. ____ is the adjective.", "option": ["He", "Painter", "Is"], "answer": "Experienced"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "None of the boys attended the class.", "option": ["boys", "attended", "class"], "answer": "None"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "Sweets will be given to each student.", "option": ["Sweets", "Will", "Given"], "answer": "Each"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "You may go either side of the road.", "option": ["You", "May", "Go"], "answer": "Either"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "What type of books do you like?", "option": ["Like", "You", "Books"], "answer": "What"},
{"test": "Adjective", "question": "Dona is more polite than Kyra.", "option": ["Dona", "Kyra", "Is"], "answer": "More polite"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "I was very grateful that he _____ (repair) my computer so promptly.", "option": ["repairs", "will be repairing", "will repair"], "answer": "repaired"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": ". Last night while sleeping, I _____ (have) a beautiful dream that my dog had given birth to puppies.", "option": ["would have", "has", "am having"], "answer": "had"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": ". If your path is being blocked, I ____(move) my vehicle out of your way.", "option": ["have moved", "moved", "moving"], "answer": "will move"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "That you are ___ (drink) while driving, aggravates your offence.", "option": ["drink", "drank", ". been drinking"], "answer": "drunk"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "My Uncle Samuel _____(be) a source of inspiration for me since I was a young boy.", "option": ["was being", "will be", "is being"], "answer": "has been"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "Except that Govind is short. sighted, he is ___________.", "option": ["inept for the post", "weak for the post", "not eligible for the post"], "answer": "fit for the post"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "In order to save the company from further loss, the employees _________________.", "option": ["formed a union", "asked for increase in salary", "went on a strike"], "answer": "decided to work extra hours"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "If you ______ your eyes you will hurt them.", "option": ["squeezes", "squeezed", "squeezing"], "answer": "squeeze"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "Although it ___ (rain) heavily this monsoon, there is a deficit of rainfall in some parts of the state.", "option": ["raining", "has been raining", ". been raining"], "answer": "rained"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "I had my hair straightened and _____ (style) at the new beauty parlour.", "option": ["styling", "has styled", "styles"], "answer": "styled"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": ". Last evening, we ____________ (go) to the mangroves by boat, when we found a rare seagull.", "option": ["have gone", "went", "have been going"], "answer": "were going"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "We should all desire _______ world where only peace prevails.", "option": ["in this", "coming to", "with in"], "answer": "for a"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "This town, once a prosperous sea port, is now a _________.", "option": ["beautiful town", "vibrant town", "flourishing town"], "answer": "heap of ruins"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "The book, in parts,is ...................", "option": ["bore", "bores", "bored"], "answer": "boring"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "In spite of many failures, he hopes to _________.", "option": ["lose", "quarrel", "get dejected"], "answer": "succeed"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "Next summer, I _____ (wear) the same wedding dress that my mother wore at her wedding.", "option": ["have worn", "was wearing", "wear"], "answer": "will be wearing"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "Identify the right option with the correct sentences.", "option": ["To teach children for, you need patience", "To teach children's you need patience.", "To teach children you need a patience."], "answer": "To teach children you need patience."},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "After _______ (finish) the work, they let the water fall on the wooden floor.", "option": ["finished", "finishes", "had finished"], "answer": "finishing"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "She is _______ good at dancing __________ singing.", "option": ["Either-neither", "Neither-or", "Either-not"], "answer": "Neither-nor"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "Prakash _________ at home for an hour but Jaya could not reach on time.", "option": ["is waiting", "will be waiting", "has waited"], "answer": "had been waiting"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "I know that you ___ (pass) the exam with flying colours.", "option": ["Pass", "Will pass", "Should pass"], "answer": "Passed"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "At the last Olympics, he ______(carry) the Indian flag during the opening day parade.", "option": ["shall carry", "carries", "will carry"], "answer": "carried"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "I like to _________ (sing) when I am tired.", "option": ["sang", "sings", "singing"], "answer": "sing"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "The police ___________ people in the neighborhood since last week.", "option": ["have been interrogating", "has interrogated", "have interrogated"], "answer": "has been interrogating"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": "He _______ (to eat) fish for lunch.", "option": ["would be eat", "was eat", "eating"], "answer": "ate"},
{"test": "Verb", "question": ". I ___ (do) my homework when she called.", "option": ["am doing", "Do", "No changes required"], "answer": "was doing"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "He _________ goes to the cinema", "option": ["carefully", "quite", "rather"], "answer": "rarely"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "She phoned me .............................", "option": ["next week", "after two days", "tomorrow"], "answer": "yesterday"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "The boy ________ walked to the stage", "option": ["heavily", "early", "neatly"], "answer": "slowly"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "You are ________ right.", "option": ["now", "well", "very"], "answer": "quite"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "_________ can you do that?", "option": ["why", "who", "whose"], "answer": "how"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "You should do it..............................", "option": ["just", "gently", "still"], "answer": "now"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": ": He is _________ in bed", "option": ["easily", "out", "regular"], "answer": "still"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "I have _________ finished the book", "option": ["regularly", "neatly", "sweetly"], "answer": "already"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "_________ we\u2019ll study gramma", "option": ["the day before yesterday", "present day", "yesterday"], "answer": "today"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "You behaved __________ yesterday", "option": ["foolish", "fooled", "fool"], "answer": "foolishly"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "Tom works really ..........................", "option": ["Tom", "works", "really"], "answer": "well"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "Come in and sit ...........................", "option": ["come", "in", "and"], "answer": "here"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": ": The bedroom is _____ the kitchen.", "option": ["the", "bedroom", "kitchen"], "answer": "above"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "_______________ have you put the notebooks?", "option": ["which", "when", "what"], "answer": "Where"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "I solved the puzzle____________", "option": ["I", "solved", "puzzle"], "answer": "easily"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "She is ______ late for work.", "option": ["she", "work", "late"], "answer": "sometimes"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "Ram _________ held the ball.", "option": ["ball", "Ram", "held"], "answer": "confidently"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "Ravi handles the puppies _______", "option": ["heavily", "lightly", "puppies"], "answer": "gently"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "The shooter missed the target badly", "option": ["mistakenly", "bad", "roughly"], "answer": "badly"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "He is very ______with his performance.", "option": ["softly", "soft", "badly"], "answer": "happy"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "Which is the correct spelling of \u2018angry\u2019 when it becomes an adverb?", "option": ["angrier", "angriest", "angry"], "answer": "angrily"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "Which of these words is an adverb?", "option": ["running", "Seeta", "beautiful"], "answer": "shyly"},
{"test": "adverb", "question": "Which of these words is an adverb?", "option": ["friendly", "table", "heavy"], "answer": "almost"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "1.\tYour request\u2014\u2014\u2013leave is under consideration.", "option": ["On", "To", "With"], "answer": "For"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "Trust ________ God", "option": ["at", "by", "for"], "answer": "in"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "She is tired _____ his attitude.", "option": ["at", "in", "for"], "answer": "of"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "Hurry up, time is running______.", "option": ["down", "left", "right"], "answer": "up"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "Bushra was sitting ______ him.", "option": ["None", "nearly", "left"], "answer": "beside"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "I have paid _______ it", "option": ["in", "by", "on"], "answer": "for"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "He does not care __________ me.", "option": ["br", "for", "to"], "answer": "about"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "This shirt is loose ______ me.", "option": ["by", "to", "to"], "answer": "for"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "Nora has given _______ smoking.", "option": ["to", "by", "for"], "answer": "up"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "Leo was annoyed _____ my performance.", "option": ["because of", "for", "about"], "answer": "by"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "Akram was excused _________ attending the class", "option": ["in", "by", "for"], "answer": "of"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "He is Newton _________ our class.", "option": ["in", "to", "for"], "answer": "of"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "What is time ______ your watch?", "option": ["None", "at", "on"], "answer": "in"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "You can never see _______my plan.", "option": ["at", "on", "in"], "answer": "through"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "Let me introduce you ____ my friends.", "option": ["about", "by", "with"], "answer": "to"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "The people did not agree ____ the leader.", "option": ["for", "by", "at"], "answer": "with"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "Anna is good  ______  studies.", "option": ["None", "in", "on"], "answer": "at"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "it is not easy ________ score.", "option": ["at", "in", "for"], "answer": "to"},
{"test": "preposition", "question": "He is too cute_______ igonere.", "option": ["by", "for", "at"], "answer": "to"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "1.\tDo not put much reliance\u2014\u2014\u2013 his promises.", "option": ["At", "With", "About"], "answer": "On"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "1.\tThe people of Iran staged a revolt \u2014\u2014\u2014 their shah.", "option": ["With", "To", "In"], "answer": "Against"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "Our body has a remarkable resistance\u2014\u2014\u2013 diseases.", "option": ["In", "With", "At"], "answer": "To"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "He has no sympathy\u2014\u2014\u2014- beggars.", "option": ["To", "In", "At"], "answer": "For"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "He showed great tenacity\u2014\u2014\u2013 purpose in bringing the task to completion.", "option": ["In", "for", "At"], "answer": "of"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "He has no trust\u2014\u2014- his own skill.", "option": ["On", "Of", "With"], "answer": "In"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "He struggled and gained a victory\u2014\u2014\u2013his enemies.", "option": ["With", "At", "Between"], "answer": "Over"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "His zeal\u2014\u2014\u2014work is known to everybody.", "option": ["To", "Of", "On"], "answer": "For"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "There is no need for you to be so sensitive\u2014\u2014- criticism. For To With At", "option": ["With", "By", "For"], "answer": "To"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "I can\u2019t help you, I am short \u2014\u2014\u2013of money at present.", "option": ["From", "On", "At"], "answer": "Of"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "He was shy \u2014\u2014\u2014\u2013 fighting with his opponent.", "option": ["On", "With", "To"], "answer": "Of"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "This pen is similar \u2014\u2014\u2014 the one I bought the last month.", "option": ["With", "Of", "For"], "answer": "To"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "He may be slow \u2014\u2014\u2014- understanding.", "option": ["With", "To", "For"], "answer": "At"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "I am thankful to you \u2014\u2014\u2014 your kindness.", "option": ["In", "From", "Of"], "answer": "For"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "He was true \u2014\u2014\u2014 his master.", "option": ["Of", "In", "With"], "answer": "To"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "This passport is valid \u2014\u2014\u2013 five years.", "option": ["In", "Of", "To"], "answer": "For"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "I am weary \u2014\u2014\u2014\u2013 your lame excuses.", "option": ["To", "In", "For"], "answer": "Of"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "I assure you \u2014\u2014\u2014 my cooperation.", "option": ["In", "To", "For"], "answer": "Of"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "The vendor walked _________the street to sell fruits.", "option": ["None", "against", "after"], "answer": "across"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "The road led________the forest.", "option": ["by", "against", "across"], "answer": "along"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "The child hid _________the trees.", "option": ["before", "across", "about"], "answer": "among"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "They have a dishwasher ________home.", "option": ["in", "by", "to"], "answer": "at"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "They went to Dubai_________ a week.", "option": ["at", "by", "on"], "answer": "for"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "The best friends sat________each other.", "option": ["none", "next for", "next in"], "answer": "next to"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "Their bedroom is right ___________ ours.", "option": ["at", "in", "towards"], "answer": "underneath"},
{"test": "use of preposition", "question": "The dog jumped________his lap.", "option": ["into", "to", "in"], "answer": "onto"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Hardly had he left \u2026\u2026\u2026. his brother came.", "option": ["then", "than", "that"], "answer": "when"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "He is no other \u2026\u2026\u2026 my friend.", "option": ["then", "but", "when"], "answer": "than"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "He saw a snake \u2026\u2026\u2026he awoke.", "option": ["None", "than", "then"], "answer": "when"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "She is \u2026\u2026\u2026. good \u2026\u2026\u2026. bad.", "option": ["either- not", "neither-or", "neithe-than"], "answer": "neither-nor"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "The cellphone is both cheap \u2026\u2026\u2026. best.", "option": ["than", "or", "then"], "answer": "and"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "-Srishti will go \u2026\u2026\u2026. Sanju goes.", "option": ["although", "then", "than"], "answer": "if"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "She is wise\u2026\u2026\u2026.. timid.", "option": ["however", "but", "yet"], "answer": "and"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Neither he \u2026\u2026\u2026 his friend is good.", "option": ["or", "and", "but"], "answer": "nor"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "The officer asked the peon \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..why he was late", "option": ["that", "if", "but"], "answer": "None"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Both Ajay\u2026\u2026\u2026.. Vijay are intelligent.", "option": ["if", "else", "or"], "answer": "and"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "No Sooner did the thief see the public \u2026\u2026\u2026. he ran away.", "option": ["then", "and", "but"], "answer": "than"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Abhinav \u2026\u2026\u2026 his brothers was going to Mumbai.", "option": ["but", "yet", "None"], "answer": "together with"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "He behaves \u2026\u2026\u2026. he were the captain of the team.", "option": ["and", "nor", "None"], "answer": "as if"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Either Rupali\u2026\u2026\u2026 Sonali is going to attend the meeting.", "option": ["and", "but", "nor"], "answer": "or"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Neither Nirmal \u2026\u2026\u2026. Ashwinee is going to listen the speech.", "option": ["and", "but", "or"], "answer": "nor"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Ravi \u2026\u2026\u2026 Prakash are going to Kolkata.", "option": ["or", "nor", "but"], "answer": "and"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Rice \u2026\u2026. curry is my usual breakfast.", "option": ["than", "but", "then"], "answer": "and"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Make hay \u2026\u2026\u2026 the sun shines.", "option": ["though", "before", "after"], "answer": "while"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Although he is rich, \u2026\u2026\u2026 he is unhappy.", "option": ["but", "still", "so"], "answer": "yet"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Wait here \u2026\u2026. I come back.", "option": ["after", "before", "until"], "answer": "till"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "He must go away \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..he will be beaten.", "option": ["otherwise", "and", "else"], "answer": "or"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "God loves good men men love God.\u2026\u2026.. good.", "option": ["but", "that", "or"], "answer": "and"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "He was late \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026. he was not punished.", "option": ["but", "yet", "still"], "answer": "therefore"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Walk slowly \u2026\u2026. You May fall,", "option": ["and", "for", "so"], "answer": "otherwise"},
{"test": "Conjunction", "question": "Work hard, \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 you will fail.", "option": ["if", "by", "until"], "answer": "or"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "___________ ! That really hurt.", "option": ["Hooray", "Yes", "Bravo"], "answer": "Ouch"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "_________, I have really missed you.", "option": ["really", "I", "really"], "answer": "Geez"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "____________ , I better put my books away.", "option": ["Whew", "No", "Aww"], "answer": "Well"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "___________ ! You are finally finished with this test.", "option": ["Hmmm", "No", "Oops"], "answer": "Hooray"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "______!  That is the most beautiful sunset I've ever seen!", "option": ["Oh no!", "Oops!", "Yuck!"], "answer": "Oh my!"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "The following interjection best communicates the emotion \"surprise\".", "option": ["Hey!", "Gee whiz!", "Drat!"], "answer": "Ooh-la-la!"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "_________, I'm not sure this is correct.", "option": ["I'm", "sure", "umm"], "answer": "Hmm"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "__________! I found the answer!", "option": ["answer", "found", "umm"], "answer": "Aha"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "__________! It was a wonderful show.", "option": ["sigh", "wow", "wonderful"], "answer": "Bravo"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "__________! The cake looks delicious!", "option": ["wow", "Hooray", "Hi"], "answer": "Yum"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "_____________, I spilled my milk.", "option": ["wow", "Hi", "Hooray"], "answer": "Oops"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "__________! How are you?", "option": ["Hey!", "Ouch!", "Hooray!"], "answer": "Hi !"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "A strong interjection is punctuated with a...", "option": ["period", "comma", "question mark"], "answer": "exclamation mark"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "A mild interjection is punctuated with a....................", "option": ["period", "question mark", "exclamation mark"], "answer": "comma"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "In interjection can be mostly found........................", "option": ["at the end of a sentence", "in the middle of a sentence", "it doesn't matter where it is"], "answer": "in the beginning of a sentence"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "______________, I thought the quiz was tomorrow.", "option": ["I", "though", "was"], "answer": "oh"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "pick the sentence with the interjection", "option": ["There is gum on the floor.", "I am going to leave now.", "He loves football."], "answer": "Yes! I passed my test!"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "_____________, I thought the quiz was tomorrow.", "option": ["I", "though", "was"], "answer": "Oh"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "What is an interjection?", "option": ["is a word that shows a relationship among other words in the sentence a person,", "answer choices is a word that connects words, sentences or phrases.", "place or thing"], "answer": "a word or phrase that expresses emotion or feelings, gives a command or fills a silence."},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "____________ ! You are finally finished with this test.", "option": ["No", "Hmmm", "Oops"], "answer": "Hooray"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "______________ , I better put my books away.", "option": ["Whew", "Aww", "No"], "answer": "Well"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "____________! That really hurt!", "option": ["Bravo", "Yes", "Hooray"], "answer": "Ouch"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "Does this sentence include an interjection: I am so excited for Friday night!", "option": ["might be", "maybe", "yes"], "answer": "no"},
{"test": "Interjection", "question": "A mild interjection is punctuated with a......................", "option": ["exclamation mark", "question mark", "period"], "answer": "comma"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "New York is ____ large city.", "option": ["no article", "the", "an"], "answer": "a"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Are you attending ____reception today.", "option": ["no article", "an", "a"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "___________Oranges are grown in Nagpur", "option": ["the", "an", "a"], "answer": "no article"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "She wants to become ____engineer.", "option": ["the", "no article", "a"], "answer": "an"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "__________lion is a ferocious animal.", "option": ["no article", "an", "a"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "_____________ unit means a measurement", "option": ["no article", "an", "a"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "He is _________honest official.", "option": ["no article", "the", "a"], "answer": "an"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Taj mahal is built of ________ marble.", "option": ["the", "an", "a"], "answer": "no article"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "He is __________ European", "option": ["the", "no article", "an"], "answer": "a"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Let us play _________ chess.", "option": ["the", "an", "a"], "answer": "no article"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "I go to Madurai by ___________Vaigai Express.", "option": ["no article", "an", "a"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "He hopes to join __________university soon", "option": ["the", "no article", "an"], "answer": "a"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Let us go to a restaurant and have _________coffee.", "option": ["the", "no article", "an"], "answer": "a"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "It is ___________absurd story.", "option": ["no article", "the", "a"], "answer": "an"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "I want to eat ____ apple.", "option": ["no article", "a", "the"], "answer": "an"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "___________ Pandiyan Express is very popular.", "option": ["no article", "an", "a"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Nepal will become ____ super power shortly.", "option": ["the", "no article", "an"], "answer": "a"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Ram was ________best student in the class.", "option": ["no article", "an", "a"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Please give me __________useful gift.", "option": ["no article", "the", "an"], "answer": "a"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "__________ apples I bought are sour.", "option": ["no article", "an", "a"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "The thief was sent to ____prison.", "option": ["no article", "an", "a"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "__________meat you cooked tasted good.", "option": ["no article", "a", "an"], "answer": "the"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Our city will have ____________university soon", "option": ["no article", "the", "an"], "answer": "a"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Would you like to have _____ cup of tea ?", "option": ["no article", "the", "an"], "answer": "a"},
{"test": "Article", "question": "Take ___________ umbrella with you.", "option": ["no article", "the", "a"], "answer": "an"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "Complete the sentence: John did not do well in the class because ____________", "option": ["he studied bad.", "he was not good study wise.", "he was a badly student."], "answer": "he failed to study properly."},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": ": The more she worked____________", "option": ["she achieved not enough.", "she was achieving less.", "she did not achieve enough."], "answer": "less she achieved."},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "__________the best car to buy is a ferrrai.", "option": ["Because it lasts a long time, and it is very economical,", "Because of its durability and it is economical,", "Because of its durability and economy wise it is better than all the others"], "answer": "Because of its durability and economy,"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "When Harry arrived home after a hard day at work, ___________", "option": ["his wife was sleeping.", "his wife has been sleeping.", "his wife is  sleeping"], "answer": "his wife was sleeping."},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "People all over the world are starving___________", "option": ["greater in numbers.", "in more numbers.", "more numerously."], "answer": "in greater numbers."},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "It was not until she arrived in class .\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026..realized she had forgotten her book", "option": ["while she", "if she", "and she"], "answer": "that she"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "John has not been able to recall where ___________.", "option": ["does she live  .", "lived the girl.", "did she live."], "answer": "she lives."},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "Ben would have studied medicine if he ________ to a medical school.", "option": ["could be able to enter", "was admitted", "were admitted"], "answer": "had been admitted"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "He entered a university __________.", "option": ["when he had sixteen years", "at age sixteen years\u2019 old", "at the age of sixteen"], "answer": "when sixteen years were his age"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": ". The Starks were told to \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026........", "option": ["talk all they wanted", "make lots of expressions", "talk with their minds open"], "answer": "speak freely"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "Those students do not like to read novels _______ their textbooks.", "option": ["in any case", "leaving out of the question", "forgetting about"], "answer": "much less"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "He \u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026 looked forward to the new venture.", "option": ["with great eagerness", "eagernessly", "in a state of increasing eagerness"], "answer": "eagerly"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "The people were told to vacate their houses immediately ___________.", "option": ["in the time", "by the time.", "at the time when the water began to go up"], "answer": "when the water raised when the water began to rise"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "Which of these is not a type of subordinate clause?", "option": ["Adverb", "Noun", "Adjective"], "answer": "Verb"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "The cricket bat ___________ is mine.", "option": ["with a broken handle", "with a broke handle", "and a broken handle"], "answer": "which has a broken handle"},
{"test": "Clauses", "question": "Choose the correct statement:", "option": ["I\u2019ll write a letter when I will reach Mumbai.", "I\u2019ll write a letter when I shall reach Mumbai.", "I\u2019ll write a letter as I reach Mumbai."], "answer": "I\u2019ll write a letter when I reach Mumbai."},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which of the following words is in singular form?", "option": ["formulae", "agenda", "oases"], "answer": "radius"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which of the following words is not plural?", "option": ["feet", "lice", "men"], "answer": "news"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "The plural form of \u2018Apex\u2019 is_________.", "option": ["apexeon", "apexos", "apices"], "answer": "apexes"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "What is the plural form of \u2018Magus\u2019?", "option": ["Magu", "Maguses", "Magis"], "answer": "Magi"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "The plural form of spectrum is_________________.", "option": ["Spectrums", "Specta", "Species"], "answer": "Spectra"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which one is in singular number?", "option": ["Criteria", "Data", "Agenda"], "answer": "Index"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which of the following is a singular noun?", "option": ["Syllabi", "Media", "Phenomena"], "answer": "Premium"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "what is the plural form of \u2018Furniture\u2019?", "option": ["Furnitures", "Many furnitures", "Much Furnitures"], "answer": "Furniture"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "The _________ of the office will be sold.", "option": ["Machineries", "baggages", "furnitures"], "answer": "equipment"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which one is plural number?", "option": ["fiveses", "fivess", "five"], "answer": "five\u2019s"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "What is the plural form of the word \u201cSeraph\u201d?", "option": ["Seraphs", "Serapic", "Seraphes"], "answer": "Seraphim"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which one of the nouns has no singular form?", "option": ["brethren", "men", "horses"], "answer": "measles"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "All of the people at the AAME conference are__________.", "option": ["Mathematic teachers", "Mathematic teachers", "Mathematic\u2019s teachers"], "answer": "Mathematics teachers"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which of the following words is not plural?", "option": ["men", "feet", "lice"], "answer": "news"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which of the following is in plural form?", "option": ["Cherub", "Gallows", "Vertebra"], "answer": "Banditti"},
{"test": "Number", "question": "Which of the following is a singular noun?", "option": ["Syllabi", "Media", "Phenomena"], "answer": "Premium"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "John did not do well in the class because ____________", "option": ["he studied bad", "he was not good study wise h", "e was a badly student"], "answer": "he failed to study properly"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "I met him after a long time, but he gave me the cold shoulder.", "option": ["scolded me", "insulted me", "abused me"], "answer": "ignored me"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "A man of straw", "option": ["A very active person", "An unreasonable person", "A worthy fellow"], "answer": "A man of no substance"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "A man of straw", "option": ["A very active person", "An unreasonable person", "A worthy fellow"], "answer": "A man of no substance"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To pick holes", "option": ["To find some reason to quarrel", "To cut some part of an item", "To destroy something"], "answer": "To criticise someone"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To have an axe to grind", "option": ["To have no result", "To work for both sides", "To fail to arouse interest"], "answer": "A private end to serve"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "Sobhraj could be easily arrested because the police were tipped off in a advance.", "option": ["Toppled over", "Bribed", "Threatened"], "answer": "Given advance information"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "A black sheep", "option": ["A lucky person", "An ugly person", "A partner who takes no share of the profits"], "answer": "None of these"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To put one\u2019s hand to plough", "option": ["To take up agricultural farming", "Take interest in technical work", "To get entangled into unnecessary things"], "answer": "To take a difficult task"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To drive home", "option": ["To find one\u2019s roots", "Back to original position", "To return to place of rest"], "answer": "To emphasise"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To set one\u2019s face against", "option": ["To get out of difficulty", "To judge by appearance", "To look at one steadily"], "answer": "To oppose with determination"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To beg the question", "option": ["To refer to", "To be discussed", "To raise objections"], "answer": "To take for granted"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To be above board", "option": ["To have a good height", "To try to be beautiful", "They have no debts"], "answer": "To be honest in any business deal"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To catch a tartar", "option": ["To trap wanted criminal with great difficulty", "To deal with a person who is more than one\u2019s match", "To meet with disaster"], "answer": "To catch a dangerous person"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To hit the nail right on the head", "option": ["To announce one\u2019s fixed views", "To destroy one\u2019s reputation", "To teach someone a lesson"], "answer": "To do the right thing"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To play second fiddle", "option": ["To be happy, cheerful and healthy", "To reduce importance of one\u2019s senior", "To do back seat driving"], "answer": "To support the role and view of another person"},
{"test": "Phrases", "question": "To end in smoke", "option": ["To make completely understand", "To excite great applause", "To overcome someone"], "answer": "To ruin oneself"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Each country is responsible to keep ___________ for peace in region.", "option": ["work", "works", "worked"], "answer": "working"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "I'm sorry the house is not available any longer. It ______ to a timber tycoon.", "option": ["is sold", "was being sold", "will be sold"], "answer": "has been sold"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "I ______ an appointment with the dentist soon.", "option": ["have made", "make", "made"], "answer": "will make"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "One must consider about any matter before ___________ it.", "option": ["decided", "decide", "decides"], "answer": "deciding"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "She ___________ for effective follow up of agenda.", "option": ["be call", "call", "will called"], "answer": "called"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Why ___________ you break your promise?", "option": ["is", "done", "does"], "answer": "did"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Charles ______ his father in the shop until school ______ .", "option": ["was helping-will start", "helped-was starting", "has helped-is starting"], "answer": "is helping-starts"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Do you know, I ___________ asked by them to be honest?", "option": ["are", "were", "is"], "answer": "am"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "My father ___________ newspaper after getting up.", "option": ["read", "is read", "am read"], "answer": "reads"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "The clerk ______ the money from the bank by one o-clock.", "option": ["A has withdrawn", "D had been withdrawing", "C is withdrawing"], "answer": "will have withdrawn"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Ai Ling ______ to Manhattan is 1997.", "option": ["has been transferred", "should be transferred", "is transferred"], "answer": "was transferred"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Which of these is used to express habitual actions?", "option": ["Present perfect tense", "Present continuous tense", "Past continuous tense"], "answer": "Simple present tense"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Correct the incorrect statement", "option": ["I was loving it", "I have been loving it", "I shall be loving it"], "answer": "I love it"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Wait for us at home until I ___________ from office.", "option": ["returned", "am return", "returns"], "answer": "return"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Twelve terrorists ___________ in air strike.", "option": ["kill", "kills", "is killed"], "answer": "killed"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "A journalist ______ to interview you later today.", "option": ["had come", "came", "has been coming"], "answer": "will be coming"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "Passengers ______ to smoke in the train.", "option": ["was not allowed", "will not allow", "had not allowed"], "answer": "are not allowed"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "The people next door ______ a lot of noise until past midnight.", "option": ["have making", "are making", "was making"], "answer": "were making"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "To which of the tenses does the statement belong? I shall be meeting Neha in the market.", "option": ["Future perfect tense", "Simple future tense", "Future perfect continuous tense"], "answer": "Future continuous tense"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "I met Ruchi in Nagpur yesterday. I ______ her a week before.", "option": ["was seeing", "had been seeing", "saw"], "answer": "had seen"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "When I went back to my hometown three years ago, I found that a lot of changes ______.", "option": ["were taken place", "are taken place", "have taken place"], "answer": "had taken place"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "He said that he ______ tomorrow.", "option": ["will come", "has been coming", "will be coming"], "answer": "would come"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "There ___________ lots of hidden feelings and emotions behind every faces.", "option": ["was", "have being", "were be"], "answer": "are"},
{"test": "Tense", "question": "They ___________ asked to give opinion in their own words.", "option": ["have being", "could be", "might"], "answer": "may be"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "____________ your father ___________ at the Medical College? - Yes, he does.", "option": ["do - work", "did - work", "has - worked"], "answer": "does - work"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "He ___ to school at 7:30 and ___ at 2 o\u2019clock.", "option": ["go-come back", "went-is coming back", "was going-has come back"], "answer": "goes-comes back"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "You ___ not ___ your soup. - I\u2019m sorry. I\u2019m not hungry.", "option": ["are-eat", "has-eaten", "did-ate"], "answer": "are -eating"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "Who __________ French in your family? -I ___________ .", "option": ["speaking-did", "spoke-do", "speak-does"], "answer": "speaks-do"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "she still ____________ how to prepare Chinese food.", "option": ["did not know", "know", "don\u2019t know"], "answer": "doesn\u2019t know"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "The aims of the course ___________ me willing to begin.", "option": ["makes", "is making", "were made"], "answer": "make"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "Listen! Somebody __________ in the next room.", "option": ["sing", "sings", "are singing"], "answer": "is singing"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "- _________________ life _____________ on Mars? - No, it ______________.", "option": ["Had-existed-had", "Has-existed-had", "Did-existed- didn\u2019t"], "answer": "Does-exist -doesn\u2019t"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "I ___ this man at all.", "option": ["have known", "knew", "know"], "answer": "don\u2019t know"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "The boys ____________ four English books this year.", "option": ["read", "had read", "reads"], "answer": "have read"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "I know he reads every book I ___ ever ___ of.", "option": ["null-hear", "null-heard", "has-heard"], "answer": "have-heard"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "Nothing will make him ____________ back to her.", "option": ["to come", "coming", "came"], "answer": "come"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "Listen! Someone _______________ at the door.", "option": ["knocks", "to knock", "has knocked"], "answer": "is knocking"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "\u201cThis thief _______________ usually promise to steal again,\u201d said Sherlock Holmes.", "option": ["won\u2019t", "didn\u2019t", "isn\u2019t"], "answer": "doesn\u2019t"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "Samuel says he\u2019s 25 years old, but nobody ___ him.", "option": ["is believing", "don\u2019t believe", "had believed"], "answer": "believes"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "The sea ___ to those who ___ to listen to it.", "option": ["speaks-likes", "speak-like", "speak-likes"], "answer": "speaks-like"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "Take your umbrella. It ___ .", "option": ["was raining", "rained", "rains"], "answer": "is raining"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "We can\u2019t disturb him now. He ___ .", "option": ["operate", "has operated", "will operate"], "answer": "is operating"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "The children of the man who works with me _________________ the window this morning.", "option": ["were broken", "break", "broke"], "answer": "have broken"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "\u201cWho ______________ this picture?\u201d the teacher asks.", "option": ["drawn", "have drawn", "draws"], "answer": "has drawn"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "Do you _____ chocolate milk?", "option": ["liking", "be like", "likes"], "answer": "like"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "He _____ not want to go to the movies.", "option": ["do", "Doing", "is"], "answer": "does"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "He ____________ now.", "option": ["wants breakfast", "walks home", "plays tennis."], "answer": "runs fast"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "Robert __________ not go to my school.", "option": ["is", "am", "are"], "answer": "does"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "My parents _____ in a two-bedroom apartment.", "option": ["is live", "are live", "lives"], "answer": "live"},
{"test": "Present Tense", "question": "You _____ so happy today!", "option": ["looks", "looking", "be"], "answer": "seem"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "She never _____________ to eat soup.", "option": ["like", "had liked", "would not like"], "answer": "liked"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "\u201cI\u2019ll drink tea from this tin mug.\u201d \u201cWhere ______________ you ____________ it?\u201d", "option": ["were-found", "did -found", "do -find"], "answer": "did -find"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "It was dark and cold. At one moment he thought that he ________________ his way.", "option": ["lost", "will lose", "was lost"], "answer": "had lost"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "I didn\u2019t know anyone in the city where I ________________ to get.", "option": ["did try", "have tried", "would try"], "answer": "was trying"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "Why _____________ you go to the plant? - I ________________ no time.", "option": ["do -had", "did -hadn\u2019t", "didn\u2019t-hadn\u2019t"], "answer": "didn\u2019t-had"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "A policeman ______________ me crossing the street yesterday.", "option": ["seen", "will see", "has seen"], "answer": "saw"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "Arthur____________ all his exams by 5 o\u2019clock yesterday.", "option": ["passed", "has been passed", "has passed"], "answer": "had passed"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "He evidently ________________ his shoes for a very long time. They were worn-out.", "option": ["was wearing", "are wearing", "were wearing"], "answer": "had been wearing"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "So, the invisible man _______________ into the shop and ______________ down.", "option": ["comes-walked", "didn\u2019t come-walk", "will come-walked"], "answer": "came-walked"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "Who ______________ the leading part?", "option": ["did play", "play", "would play"], "answer": "played"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "One day the boys found a man in the forest. He ____________________.", "option": ["will die", "had been dying", "had died"], "answer": "was dying"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "During his school years Cronin _____________ great interest in literature.", "option": ["take", "had taken", "has taken"], "answer": "took"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "He _________________ the box yesterday, because he had to do it.", "option": ["had opening", "would open", "opens"], "answer": "opened"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "She ______________ you a letter three weeks ago.", "option": ["has sent", "was sending", "send"], "answer": "sent"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "Long ago people _____________ little about those minerals.", "option": ["knowed", "will know", "had known"], "answer": "knew"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "I _________ to the mall after school.", "option": ["going", "gone", "go"], "answer": "went"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "My brother ___________ a bear an hour ago.", "option": ["seen", "none", "sees"], "answer": "saw"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "______________ Mike visit his grandmother last night?", "option": ["Are", "Do", "Does"], "answer": "Did"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "Alex did not _______________ last weekend.", "option": ["working", "worked", "been working"], "answer": "work"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "_____________ Judy and Liz at last month's meeting?", "option": ["Was", "is", "Are"], "answer": "Were"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "We ______________ not happy after the sad ending.", "option": ["is", "did", "was"], "answer": "were"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "___________ you see Jody's new dog yesterday?", "option": ["Are", "Is", "Do"], "answer": "Did"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "Sorry, I ____________ hear you at the door.", "option": ["wasn't", "is not", "am not"], "answer": "didn't"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "I __________ English for two years.", "option": ["studying", "study", "had been studying"], "answer": "studied"},
{"test": "Past Tense", "question": "What _____ you eat for lunch yesterday?", "option": ["do", "was", "were"], "answer": "did"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "I______________ to start a new life tomorrow.", "option": ["to be going", "is going", "shall go"], "answer": "am going"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "Mark ____________ into the army next year.", "option": ["was going", "goes", "would go"], "answer": "will go"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "They ___ dinner at this time tomorrow.", "option": ["will have", "are having", "having had"], "answer": "will be having"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "What\u2019s happened to your hair? Your mother _________________it.", "option": ["didn\u2019t like", "liked", "would like"], "answer": "won\u2019t like"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "I ___ if you come too late tomorrow.", "option": ["will sleep", "am sleeping", "sleep"], "answer": "shall be sleeping"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "Be quick or we _______________ for school.", "option": ["are late", "is late", "have been late"], "answer": "shall be late"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "What ___ you ___ next Sunday?", "option": ["were -doing", "have -done", "are -done"], "answer": "are -doing"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "I think I _____________ a cassette recorder and use it in class.", "option": ["buy", "am buying", "would buy"], "answer": "shall buy"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "We _______________ for Niagara tomorrow.", "option": ["had to leave", "left", "have left"], "answer": "are leaving"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "I\u2019ll ask him what he ___ for lunch.", "option": ["was having", "should have", "would have"], "answer": "are having"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "Who ___________ for a walk tomorrow?", "option": ["go", "doesn\u2019t go", "didn\u2019t go"], "answer": "will go"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "They ____________ their English exam at this time tomorrow.", "option": ["will take", "is taking", "would take"], "answer": "will be taking"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "My boss ___________ some V.I.P\u2019s tomorrow.", "option": ["will be received", "receive", "will have received"], "answer": "is receiving"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "Ask him when the engineers ________________ finish the talks.", "option": ["will", "would", "had"], "answer": "have"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "He ___ to learn French next year.", "option": ["was going", "will be going", "are going"], "answer": "is going"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "All the children _____________ on an excursion next week.", "option": ["go", "went", "have gone"], "answer": "will go"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "___________ you _______________ at 6 tomorrow?", "option": ["will-sleep", "do-sleep", "were-sleeping"], "answer": "will-be sleeping"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "I shall be back by 6 and I hope you _______________ a good sleep by that time.", "option": ["have had", "would have", "will have"], "answer": "will have had"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "This time tomorrow we __________ probably ____________ fishing.", "option": ["are-will", "null-shall", "shall-null"], "answer": "shall-be"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "What ____________ you ______________ at 6 tomorrow?", "option": ["will-do", "was-doing", "is-doing"], "answer": "will-be doing"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "By the end of the first term we _________________ many English books.", "option": ["shall be read", "read", "have read"], "answer": "shall have read"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "What ___ you ___ at 6 tomorrow?", "option": ["did-do", "do-did", "do-do"], "answer": "will-be doing"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "He _____________ for you at 7 in the evening next Sunday.", "option": ["was waiting", "were waiting", "have waited"], "answer": "will be waiting"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "He _____ arrive on time.", "option": ["shall", "not", "is"], "answer": "will"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "We will _____ what your father says.", "option": ["look", "to see", "seeing"], "answer": "see"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "I don't ________ go swimming today.", "option": ["thought", "I  think", "I'll  thinking"], "answer": "think"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "We won't ________ until we get there.", "option": ["knowing", "have know", "be knowin"], "answer": "know"},
{"test": "Future Tense", "question": "Will you ________ at the rehearsal on Saturday?", "option": ["none", "have", "go"], "answer": "be"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "She_____________read poetry when she was six.", "option": ["can", "has", "will"], "answer": "could"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "___________________I come in, please?", "option": ["do", "will", "shall"], "answer": "may"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "I ______________like to see your book.", "option": ["may", "can", "should"], "answer": "would"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "We______________better consult a doctor.", "option": ["have", "has", "had"], "answer": "may"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "You______________not enter my room unless I call you.", "option": ["will", "may", "could"], "answer": "shall"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "The author travels back ______________his youth.", "option": ["in", "for", "by"], "answer": "to"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "One must try ________________best to achieve success.", "option": ["his", "her", "one's"], "answer": "their"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "Her________________is coming to Delhi.", "option": ["sisters-in-law", "sister-in-laws", "sister-in-laws"], "answer": "sister-in-law"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "I am ________________of reading.", "option": ["enjoy", "like", "fond"], "answer": "found"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "Nayan enjoys_________________.", "option": ["to swim", "having swam", "swim"], "answer": "swimming"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "My book is _______________than yours.", "option": ["more costly", "much costly", "costliest"], "answer": "costlier"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "It is a \u2014\u2014-club, so girls cannot enter.", "option": ["boy", "none", "boys"], "answer": "boy\u2019s"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "You stand a good chance ______________the match.", "option": ["to win", "in winning", "for winning"], "answer": "of winning"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "This is the first attempt______________writing poetry.", "option": ["in", "at", "on"], "answer": "for"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "Your_______________at the meeting is absolutely necessary.", "option": ["present", "presenting", "having present"], "answer": "presence"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "Their intention _______________suspicious.", "option": ["were", "as", "are"], "answer": "look"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "The lamp fell__________________the table and smashed into pieces.", "option": ["of", "out of", "from"], "answer": "off"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "They ______________not know me.", "option": ["are", "does", "is"], "answer": "do"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "Acceptance \u2014\u2014\u2013dowry is also a crime.", "option": ["to", "from", "by"], "answer": "of"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "They traveled ______________car.", "option": ["with", "in", "from"], "answer": "by"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "My hair_____________grey.", "option": ["look", "by", "are"], "answer": "is"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "There______________two grey hairs on your head.", "option": ["is", "were", "was"], "answer": "are"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "The members of my family _________________out for their various works.", "option": ["is", "to", "for"], "answer": "are"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "I ________________a terrible dream last night.", "option": ["got", "had seen", "have seen"], "answer": "saw"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "My uncle is a man _____________consequence.", "option": ["in", "with", "from"], "answer": "of"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "The child was not _______________to play.", "option": ["allow", "allowable", "allows"], "answer": "allowed"},
{"test": "Word", "question": "My mother reacted ___________________to my words.", "option": ["angry", "anger", "angered"], "answer": "angrily"}]
